hi welcome back to the online retreat
uh the wheel of life retreat hi
slamatta tanka
and i'd like to thank alison for coming
and translating
16 is called a life to live
and each one is walking through the
wheel of life
and pretty much they're in only two of
the lengths
we cover a whole human life
this is my uh kids painters kid painters
from nepal
indiana nepal
and they have said that this lady is
supposed to be a pregnant lady
is a difficult word it has been
mistranslated many times
it can mean possible
it can mean becoming
manchadi uh it can mean your whole life
it doesn't mean any of those here okay
and i think it was a big breakthrough my
own teacher taught me
this you have to think of the word
means karma which is ripe
and then it rained
[Music]
and it woke up all the workers in the
factory
inside the seat
right
[Music]
he's like wake up everybody we got work
to do yes
and so during those few months time
uh we finished those two preparation
preparing the factory to open
fabric
number eight and link number nine
and on top of that we did high powered
understanding
about seeds which makes good seeds open
faster and bigger
[Music]
so because of those two ideas
the second link which is called duchenne
tibetan and sanskara
in sanskrit
uh you know you walk into the kitchen
and your
husband yells at you
at
it's pressed on the mind
okay my dog is not only blind and dead
okay i think saya
and you know we try to lift the pupil
off very carefully
rub into the carpet
power so the verb here
good good goodbye means that smell gets
rubbed into the carpet
because this is the karma i'm saying i'm
not stupid you're stupid
and this is going to be important later
on
carpet where the stinky is rubbed into
the corner
uh it's like the watermelon seed was
just put under the dirt
ini party pizza manga young
the water what's the fertilizer we
finished it in the last class
uh in the last class we finished what's
the water and what's the fertilizer
my husband
no idea that her kids
are going to be bad for many weeks
because of what she said to her husband
that's it
and fertilizer by her negative coffee
meditation and by her misunderstanding
[Music]
tremendous power repeat two
two men
then what power does it have now after
her negative coffee meditation
a new lifetime can project a new
lifetime similar pensacola
link number 10.
we're represented by a pregnant woman
alina
let's open the the sprout comes out
and uh of a birth
of a child being born
i think a lot about these images like
arrow in the eye
coming out of a woman
water
in these ancient paintings
these must have been very very shocking
movie about this wheel of life and not
not paintings
and i think someday it would be
interesting to make a real
evocative movie like big emotion
[Music]
somebody has i in the fact i
online i tried to find someone who got
shot with an arrow in the either
it did happen once and the person went
to the hospital
online
but these pictures are are supposed to
like freak us out you know
now that the seed was given its water
and its
fertilizer by the negative coffee
meditations
crossing
into one of the four kinds of birth
and at the moment after the crossing
number 11
rebirth
is
countless times there's no beginning
the first time i heard that it was very
uncomfortable for me
to think that there was a big
feel comfortable if we think there was a
beginning
nothing can start unless somebody else
something else moves
before then
so you could really translate this link
number 11. you could always translate it
as
rebirth
and because we don't know what's the
four kinds of birds
and he doesn't mention them in the text
we should go to another book and and get
a nice uh
commentary on this one
recommended
now you can divide all the kinds of
birth into four
i know that batman back is a more genius
clay than me
and i remember this was the first book i
ever studied with my teacher
and then you know after many years you
learn to translate it
more correctly it's not location of
birth it's the type of earth
here's the name of the fort
okay
[Music]
some beings are born from
the real birth is at the moment of
conception
but it's the conception which is when
the baby starts
sentient being at the moment of
conception
the third one is called zukiy
and it means miraculous birth
for example the christians believed that
jesus was born
without a father without a sex message
sex
and uh hindis believes that the great
yoga master patanjali
holy water he he appeared in the holy
water that his mother offered
your hands is
uh when the weather is warm and there's
a lot of
rain puddles on the ground
the ancient people they couldn't see the
eggs of the insects
so they called it a birth from warmth
and moisture
just for fun i thought you guys would
like to continue reading this text
which is related to the text being
translated by our translator
from singapore
young detective
okay so i thought you'd like to hear
some discussion about this
oh hungry ghosts also have birth from
a womb it's possible they are not just
miracle
usually we think they just born suddenly
yeah hungry ghosts but he says they can
also
be born from a womb so also is a imply
usually they are born another way but
they also have born
from ancient india india and this one is
called the story of the
lady hungry ghost
and there's a famous verse that she used
to recite
yesterday
i give birth from a woman right to uh
500 kids every day
hungry ghost kids come out of my room
every day every every
day in the daylight
you might think you know how does hungry
ghost
mom take care of her one thousand per
day hungry ghost kiss
but still i don't feel full
uh
all four kinds of birth are found with
human beings
some are born miraculously
because they're just born as a complete
person
uh i don't know the story we can look it
up
someday but he apparently he was born
miraculously
okay then there was a king
who was born from the top of the head of
his
father from warmth and moisture
orange
uh animals also have four kinds of birds
all for
foreign
yeah so part of being it remembers that
one in the moment after you
[Music]
which
which brings us to link number 12.
young
this represents the way that
people were buried or how they treated
dead bodies
in ancient india and also in tibet
if you think your job is bad at least
you are not carrying corpses to the
mountain or to the we call the burial
we call the charnel ground turtle ground
means a
very terrible place where you throw dead
bodies you just throw them on the ground
chicago
a young man
he was very very famous for secret
teachings
[Music]
two famous teachers got in the car
why the big teacher doesn't sit in the
back
this is
at that time i never finished but i
finished three or four chapters
memorizing
[Music]
hello
tell me everything we see in america
tell me what it is
no no they believe that the body the
person will come alive at the end of the
world they will go to heaven
samba flour with flour come and jump
into the top of the mountain
is not wasted that person's body is a
gift
to to these wild animals
okay
it's called death
maybe with aging
techniques
yeah then i i asked my teacher why they
call it
death with maybe some aging
well sometimes kids die in the womb
comedy
the body goes to change change change
change it never stays the same
falls apart step by step
when we say death what we mean is that
the flow
of the same body and mind is interrupted
by
so we don't say the body died or the
mind stopped
the physical
and you will live for time with no end
and uh
i'd like to end this session with kind
of a review
and i'm going to be using special images
we've had all 12 links now
and i've taught them in groups in
different days
i'd like to just review that because
it's going to be important tomorrow and
the next days
that the the first two links hang
together
you can call it ignorance and karma
skyla
i want you to think of these two kind of
hang together
comes in the kitchen
she says give me a hug and she she just
reaches out like that she doesn't say
anything
that is
and these are the five links which are
kind of
our equipment during life uh they're
what we use to express ourselves
in the fifth link our eyes ears nose
they start to
we start to get our equipment for for
contacting the outside world
and then in the seventh link we start to
have feelings about what we contact him
so you can kind of get a feeling that
links three to link seven
they kind of hang together they are the
equipment that we need to
be alive
um
really when you think about it
the most important version of eight nine
and ten
is at the end of our life
which seed is is activated in the last
moment of our consciousness
that already got a lot of water and
fertilizer but
day by
11 and 12 is a whole lifetime honest
11 is is coming into the womb
but we already came into the room in
number three
happy
and why it's not just one lifetime like
shakespeare
to find out the answer
to tomorrow's session number seventeen
and uh number two
senpai